Guide to the Second Presbyterian Church of Fayette records,1825-1859.
Second Presbyterian Church of Fayette records,1825-1859
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Second Presbyterian Church of Fayette records, 1825-1859.
6080
Second Presbyterian Church of Fayette (Canoga, N.Y.)
1 reel microfilm.
Microfilm.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Session minutes which document the acceptance and dismissal of members, selection of delegates to the Presbytery, selection of elders and trustees, and matters of church discipline. Lists of baptisms and members.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
This church was formed at Canoga in Eastern Fayette township on June 28, 1825 with eleven members. In 1834 the church, under the Geneva Presbytery built a church costing $1,700. In 1848 the pastor, Reverend Mr. Cherry, an abolitionist, led the church in withdrawing from the Presbyterian Church and in forming a Congregational organization. This decision was rescinded in 1851. In 1840 a parsonage was built, later sold, and repurchased in 1860.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Scope: Contains session minutes which document the acceptance and dismissal of members, selection of delegates to the Presbytery, selection of elders and trustees, and matters of church discipline. Periodic revivals are indicated by sudden increases in membership. Lists of members and baptisms are located in the back of the volume.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Second Presbyterian Church of Fayette (Canoga, N.Y.); Geneva Presbytery (Canoga, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Church records and registers--New York (State)--Canoga.; Presbyterian Church--New York (State)--Canoga.; Presbyterian church buildings--New York (State)--Canoga.; Congregational churches--New York (State)--Canoga.
Places:
Canoga (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Seneca County (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Minutes; Baptismal certificates
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Canoga Church Records, 1825-1859
  Items of note follow:
  - June 28, 1825
    Account of the formation of the church which lists original members and where they are from.
  - June 28, 1825
    Confession of Faith
  - June 28, 1825
    Church Covenant
  - Page 1, June 28, 1825
    First Session meeting.
  - Page 9, Oct. 8, 1825
    List of infants and adults baptised.
  - Page 13, June 16, 1826-Aug. 1829
    No records.
  - Aug. 1829-1830
  - Page 21, June 30, 1833
    Received on confession of faith, 17 members.
  - Page 34, July 5, 1837
    The Geneva Presbytery met at Canoga to ordain Charles A. Matoon.
  - Page 43, March 4, 1839
    List of causes the church will support.
  - Page 55, March 18, 1843
    Many new members.
  - Page 57, March 26, 1843
  - Page 72, March 19, 1848
  - Page 74, April 17, 1848
    Meeting to consider changing the form of church govern-ment. Church adopts Congregational form of organization.
  - Page 75, April 23, 1848
    The church instructs Rev. Cherry to withdraw the church from the Geneva Presbytery.
  - Page 79, Sept. 30, 1850
    A judiciary committee is formed.
  - Page 81, March 1853
    Decisions of page 74, 75 and 79 and first section of page 80 are rescinded.
  - Page 92, Oct. 6, 1859
    Last meeting.
  - 6 p.
    List of members of the church indicating whether dismissed, suspended, married or dead, some dated.
  - 1 p.
    List of elders, trustees and moderator, n.d.
  - 1 p.
    Membership list as above.
  - 4 p., 1834-1858
    List of baptisms of children indicating name, date, parents, date of birth and sometimes the officiating clergyman.